-你找到我的书了吗? -找到了
-Were you able to find my book? -Yeah.
但有个家伙出现
But there was this guy.
把书抢走了
He took it.
他让我告诉你
He said to tell you
斯科菲尔德的哥哥拿了那本书
that Scofield's brother has it now.
你得把他们救出来
You have to break them out of there.
LJ
莎拉
Sara
别再尝试这么做
You're never going to try anything like that again.
只是为了确认
But just to make sure,
我在车库里给你留了点东西
I left you a little something in the garage.
窗外有什么比自由更吸引人的东西么?
What's so interesting out there, other than our freedom?
出逃者还活着 证明围墙上没电
Finds are alive, so the fence is dead
是么?这里每个人都知道那围墙没用
Yeah? Everyone in here knows is that fence doesn't work,
但这也改变不了什么
and it doesn't mean a bloody thing,
因为外面有士兵把守
because there are soldiers out there
只要你在30码内他们就会把你射死
that'll shoot you dead before you get within 30 yards of it.
我得好好计划一下了 不是么?
Well, I guess I got a lot of work to do, don't I?
听着 老兄 我知道你抢了我的书
Listen, mate, I get what you're doing with my book.
他们抓走了你的女友 而你抢走了他们要的东西
They hold your girlfriend, you hold what they want.
互惠互利 Churchill 101法案
Countering needs. Churchill 101.
马上那些杂种就要来问我
Soon those bastards are going to ask me
他们所要的 我了解了多少
what progress I've made in figuring out what they want,
我就要说完全不了解 因为林肯・布鲁斯把书抢走了
and I'm going to say nil, 'cause Lincoln Burrows has the book.
知道么?
You know what?
威胁
Threatening the brother
要帮你越狱的人的哥哥
of the guy who's supposed to get you out of here
并不是个好主意
might not be the smartest move.
我没有威胁你 我们在同一条船上
I'm not threatening we're on the same team.
但如果我们因为那本书纠缠不清
But if we play games with that book,
那些想让我出去的人会采取行动的
people who want me out of here will take action
"我不在乎你们做什么 就怕你们什么也不做"
"I never worry about action, only inaction."
根据Churchill 101法案
Churchill 101.
如我所说 现在我有很多事要做
Now, like I said, I got a lot of work to do.
林肯 你还好吧?
Linc, you all right?
对不起 老弟
I'm sorry, man.
都是那东西 它快找到我了
Just all this stuff it's starting to get to me.
知道么?
You know?
听着 我们的境遇很快会改变
Listen, our situation could change very, very soon.
那个监狱掘墓人
The grave digger for the prison.
你得和他联系上
I need you to reach out to him.
告诉他什么?
And tell him what?
都写在上面了
It's all written down.
我们现在就得采取行动
But we got to get started now.
你有什么没告诉我的?
What are you not telling me?
所有人
All these people
都因为我而受伤害
that have been hurt because of me.
我很抱歉 迈克
I'm so sorry, Michael.
这是他们造成的 不是你
They did this, not you.
好吗?
Okay?
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
找到那个掘墓人
Just get to the grave digger.
我感觉我们没多少时间了
I feel like we're running out of time.
莎拉
Sara.
这场较量中我只是一个棋子 林肯
I am just a soldier in this war, Lincoln,
和你一样
just like you.
我并不想那么做的
I did not want to do that.
你能理解
Can you even comprehend the intimacy
我对那个女人下手时的感受吗?
of the mechanics of what I had to do to that woman?
那太恐怖了
It's horrible
现在 如果你和你弟弟停止耍花招
Now, if you and your brother are done playing games,
LJ会没事的
LJ will be fine.
我最不想做的事是把他一块块寄给你
If not, the last thing I want to do send millions pieces of him to you
但如果你逼我
But if you push me
即使没逼那么狠 我会这么做的
and not even that far, I will.
你叫我干什么我就干什么
I'll do anything you want.
别伤害我的儿子就好
Just don't hurt my son.
这些都取决于你
That's really up to you.
我知道这几天很难熬
I know the past few days have been hard,
我也一样
for me, as well.
如果你想聊聊
If you want to talk about it,
我理解这痛苦的感觉
I know what this pain feels like.
我只想把那个人搞出Sona
I just want to get your boy out of Sona
然后接回我儿子
and get my son back.
迈克有计划了
Michael's got a plan.
我需要细节
I need details.
我们得把某个
We need to bring someone
在监狱工作的人拉拢过来
who works at the prison onto the team.
谁?
Who?
掘墓人
The grave digger.
去做吧
Get it done.
林肯 我需要那本书
Lincoln, I'm going to need that book.
中情局把你给我的那本做了笔迹鉴定
The Company did handwriting analysis on the one you gave me,
你的字迹从高中以来就没变过
and yours hasn't changed since high school.
我们只是棋子 林肯
Just soldiers, Linc.
代表不同方 但本质是一样的
Different armies, but soldiers just the same.
打得好
Nice.
我在学校里是最棒的
I was the best in my school.
女校?
All girls?
去你的
Kiss my ass,
老兄
bro.
20美元赌你没法再投进
20 bucks says you can't do that again.
-好的 -等一下
-Bet. -Wait.
根据风向调整
Adjust for wind.
闭嘴
Shut up.
向外偏一点就好了
Just a bit outside.
老兄 你知道我现在没有钱
Hey, bro, you know I don't have that kind of verde lying around.
需要点时间
It's going to take a while.
问题在于 我没有时间了
Well, the thing is, I don't have a while.
-所以 除非 -别 别再拉拢我了
-So, unless -No, no more favors.
好吧
All right.
我能借你的十字架一用么?
Can I borrow that cross of yours?
-就拿那个做交换吧 -这是我爸给我的
-I'll take it in trade. -My dad gave me this.
还有 那甚至不是金的
Besides, it's not even real gold.
这正是我需要它的原因
That's why I need it.
听着 我会还给你的 好吗?
Look, I'll give it back, okay?
只是借
It's just a loan.
给我吧
Come on.
这次 我想知道原因
This time, I want to know why.
又是灯
It's light again.
有人正在破坏暴动后
Someone's getting fat off of everythg I built
我所建立的一切
while I rot in here.
别郁闷了
Don't get upset,
拜托
patron
我只有几个小时
I only have a few more hours.
让我们好好享受下
Let's be nice.
该死的
This motherless bitch.
阿历克斯?
Alex?
你刚到这?
You just get here?
是的
Yes.
听好了
Listen,
我一直在权衡 决定让你入伙
I've been thinking about and, uh, you're in.
我算入伙了
I'm in.
好吧
Okay.
-就这么简单? -是的
-Just like that? -Right.
我别无选择 不是吗?
I really don't have a choice, do I?
你怎么计划的?
What's the plan?
我正在想办法
I'm working on it.
与此同时 你也可以帮上我的忙
Meanwhile, I could use your help.
你需要什么?
What do you need?
黑色毡尖笔
A black felt-tipped pen.
-一支钢笔? -没错
-A pen? -Yeah.
-为什么? -有些文件
-Why? -Some documents
需要做些改动
that need altering.
稍后再给你解释 我现在就要那支笔
I'll explain it to you later, but right now, I need that pen.
-行吗? -好的
-Okay? -Yeah.
我还要对你说的是
And I'll tell you what else I need.
我要你跟我们步调一致
I need you to get your act together.
我需要你控制好自己
I need you to bring yourself
因为你那样很夺人眼球
under control, because you're attracting attention,
而那是我们不想看到的
and that we don't need.
我能控制好自己
I'm under control.
你当然可以
Of course you are.
这就是用电负荷过大的下场
This is what happens when a system is overloaded.
看到吗?
See? Look.
-该死 -断电了
-Son of a -Power is out.
搞定它
Fix it.
我只是个卡车司机
I'm a truck driver.
嘿 阿历克斯
Hey, Alex.
很高兴找到你 就是来看看
Hey, glad I found ya. Just wanted to see how
-你在这过得怎样 -非常好
-you're holding up in here. -Just dandy.
我也经历过段受煎熬的日子
Yeah, well, I've been having a tough time of it myself.
但我想我们的命不该这样
And I was figuring shouldn't be that way
我们可是唯一的正直人士
for us, seeing as how we're the only lawmen here
在这个阴曹地府里
in Taco Hell.
嘿 等会儿 阿历克斯
Hey, whoa, hang on a second there, Alex.
你和我 我们可是一队的
You and me we were a team
还记得我们在外面的时候吗?
on the outside, remember?
我是你的部下 现在依然对你忠心不二
I was your dog, and I still got a lot of bark left in me.
布拉德 我很忙 你到底想怎样?
I'm busy, Brad. What do you want?
你和斯科菲尔德在计划逃跑是吧?
You and Scofield you're up to something, right?
你可以告诉我 兄弟之间没有隔阂
You can tell me, one badge to another.
我能帮上忙
I can help.
你有黑色毡尖笔吗?
Do you have a black felt-tipped pen?
我没有
Not on me.
那你帮不了我
Then you can't help me.
我都知道了
I know.
你知道什么了?
You know what?
我知道你在计划越狱
I know you're trying to escape from here
和那个叫斯科菲尔德的家伙
with that man, Scofield.
-宝贝 -求你不要欺瞒我
Sweetheart Please, don't lie to me.
林肯・布鲁斯把一切都告诉了我
Lincoln Burrows, he told me everything.
有些非常有权势的人希望我出来
There are some very powerful people that want me out of here.
-他们让那哥俩救我出去 -为何?
And they want those brothers to get me out. Why?
我也不确定
I'm not sure.
应该和我在西雅图看到的场景有关系
Has something to do with a charter I did in Seattle.
我只知道他们的最终目的
What I do know is their end game
和我们的一样 就是让我逃出这鬼地方
is exa the same as ours, and that's me out of this hellhole.
一旦成功了
And once that happens,
你和我就会消失 永远销声匿迹
you and I will disappear forever.
但是我不想让你趟这趟浑水
But I don't want to involve you in this mess.
我想帮你啊
I want to help.
那太危险了
That's way too dangerous.
詹姆斯我不是在请求你的批准
I'm not asking your permission, James.
我是在告诉你
I'm telling you.
我自己一人也能搞定
I can do this on my own,
或者你可以把你知道的告诉我
or you can tell me what you know
然后我们共同解决
and we can work it through together.
我对发生的事情也不明白
I don't understand everything that's going on,
但是那对兄弟 他们显然试图
but these brothers, they're obviously trying
从我身上打探出信息来
to find out what they can about me.
我们看看能从他们身上了解多少
Let's see what we can discover about them.
弄清楚他们的计划 了解真实目的
Find out what their plan is, see what they're all about.
他们帮你越狱 你却不信他们?
They're trying to get you out, and you don't trust them?
我谁都不信任
I don't trust any of these guys.
你也不该相信
And yoshouldn't, either.
如果你坚持要跟此事
If you insist on getting into this,
向我保证你会加倍小心
promise me you'll be careful.
因为如果你出什么三长两短
Because God knows I will die
我也不会苟活的
if anything happens to you.
嘿
Hey.
迈克
Michael.
拿着
Here.
我说过我要的是黑色毡尖笔
I said I need a black felt-tipped pen.
那是黑色的
That's black.
这不是我需要的
It's not what I need.
继续去找
Keep looking.
他在耍你
He's playing you.
不要相信他
Do not trust him.
你那美国佬兄弟
Your amigo, the American.
他是建筑工程师 是吗?
He's a builder, an engineer, no?
老大 他可不是我的朋友
He's no amigo of mine, boss.
相信我 你绝不希望
And trust me, you do not want
和他扯上关系
to get under the covers with that
回答我 是或不是工程师?
Is he or is he not an engineer?
好吧 是的 但是
Well, yeah, but
斯科菲尔德
Scofield.
什么事?
Yeah?
你懂电路吗?
What do you know about the electricity?
停电时候就会懂吧
Only that we don't have any right now.
和你说件事情
Let me tell you something.
这部手机能让食物运进来
This phone keeps all the food coming to the gate.
这样才能保障Sona监狱的正常运转
It keeps my business running, it keeps Sona running.
断电了 电话也就不能用了
Electricity die, phone die.
-电话没了我们也完蛋 -我们完蛋 你也完蛋
Phone die, we die. We die or youdie?
小子 你知识够丰富
Boy, you have enough
但是人不够聪明
education, but you're not being smart.
我来找你 是给你机会
Now, I come to you, that is an opportunity.
放聪明些 好好把握机会
Be wise and take advantage.
现在回答我 能修复电路吗
Now, can you fix the electricity
就像你搞定水源那样
just like you fixed the water?
这可没有那么简单
It's not that simple.
水管是在监狱里的
The water pipes are inside the prison.
电线却可能是在地底
The electrical lines are probably running underground
沿着墙外排布的
along an exterior wall,
意味着电线在外面的
which means they're out there somewhere
某个禁入区
in no-man's-land.
那你能恢复电力吗?
So, you can fix the power?
上次我看到他们射杀了出去的人
Last I checked, they shoot prisoners who go out there.
所以我觉得答案是"不行"
So I'm thinking the answer is"no."
听我说
You listen to me,
听清楚了 小子
and you listen closely, water boy.
不管情况是否相似 不管有没有士兵
Like it or not, soldiers or not,
你要去禁入区
you're going out into no-man's-land.
这是自杀式任务
It's a suicide mission.
我要打几个电话
I'll make some calls.
-你要确保我安全 -尽我所能吧
And you're going to keep meafe? As best I can.
我觉得我做不到
I don't think I can do this.
不 不 不 你会帮我的
No, no, no, no, no. You will help me with this.
我也会为你做点事情的
Look, I will do something for you.
我会给你一个新枕头
I'll get you a new pillow,
鹅毛的 像我的那样 或者一台小电视
goose-feather like mine, or a small TV.
好吧
All right.
给我那间房间
Get me that.
-为什么? -这里可以享受早上第一缕阳光
Why? It's the first one to get sunlight in the morning.
你给我那间囚室 我给你电力
You get me that cell, I'll get you electricity.
好啊林肯
Hey, Linc.
兄弟 我很快就要离开你了
Look, bro, um, I'm going to be out of your way real soon.
我看到哥伦比亚招移民工人的小广告
I saw these flyers for migrant workers in Colombia.
现在是咖啡豆的收获季节
It's coffee bean season,
他们让巴拿马人去干活
and they're letting Panamanians in,
所以我想 换张身份证我就可以过关了
so I figure, with a good ID, I can pass.
大巴今天发车 好吗?
Bus leaves today, okay?
好吧 在你离开这儿之前 伙计 我
All right, well, before you get out of here, man, I
我要见个人 我需要一个翻译
I'm meeting someone, and I need a translator.
林肯我很欣赏你做的每件事
Linc, uh I appreciate everything you've done
只需要几个小时
It'll just be a couple hours.
几个小时就够了
Just a couple hours, that's it.
我15岁时 我堂兄给了我一份工作
When I was 15, my cousin told me about a job that only lasts
只消几小时 我却在少教所待了三个月
a few hours and, uh, I got three months in juvie.
没有你我做不到
I can't do this without you.
我在巴拿马 我不会说西班牙语
I'm in Panama, I don't speak the language
可是我也不能错过大巴
And I can't miss that bus.
我要挣钱 寄回家
I'm going ake money and send it home.
偷偷摸摸也好 我要做爸爸了 林肯
Underground or not, I'm going to be a dad, Linc,
你和其他人不一样 应该理解
and you out of all people should understand that.
我和詹姆斯聊过
I spoke to James.
他确认了你和我说的
He confirmed what you told me
越狱的事情
about the escape.
你和我 都有关心的人
You and I, we both have people in there
在那里
we care about.
求求你 让我帮你吧
Please let me help you.
你的西班牙语和英语一样好吗?
Your Spanish as good as your English?
是的 长官
Yes, Colonel.
我要你帮个忙
I just have one favor to ask.
只是要在门外
It's just outside of the gate.
你可以带你的人来
You, you can bring your men.
电话没电了
The phone dying.
给他一个
Make him one.
就那么点?
This is it?
不是每个人都有
Not everyone has it yet.
我们延迟了一星期 所以还有些时间
We let credit go a week, and there is still time.
钱在你那里
The money's in your veins, addicto.
没有 老大 我没用过 我发誓
No, patron. I don't use anymore. I swear to you.
我发誓 没有
I swear to you. No.
我发誓 我发誓
I swear to you. I swear to you.
振作 伙计 振作
Chin up, pal o' mine, Chin up.
知道了 长官
Si Colonel.
好的 谢谢长官
Yes, thank you, Colonel.
我们马上就到
We'll be right there.
跟我来
Come with me.
对不起 你有
Excuse me. Do you, um
你有钢笔吗?
Do you have a-a, a pen?
钢笔 不是
n. Pen. Not, um
不是那刷子
Not not the brush
是钢笔 写字的钢笔
but the pen. Pen. Pen.
没有 只有绘画笔
No, pintura.
是的 绘画笔
Yeah, yeah, pintura. Yeah.
他要离开你
He's leaving you.
他要离开你 他走了
He's leaving you, he'll be gone,
你要困在这个迷宫里了
and you'll be stuck in this maze forever.
谢谢你帮我们安排这些 长官
Thank you for arranging this for us, Colonel.
我也要拿走一些东西
I'm getting something out of this as well,
我保证
I assure you.
你确定你可以解决电力问题?
You know you can fix this electric problem?
在开始挖之前我不能确定
I won't know for sure until we can start digging,
但是 我想可以的
but yes, I think so.
我的人会打爆你的头
My men will shoot you in t back of the head
如果你老看着围墙的话 明白?
if you so much as look at the fence, eh?
还有你 老大 如果有事情发生
And you, patron, if anything goes wrong.
不仅仅是他小命不保
it will not only be his life that is lost.
你也得承担责任
You have my word on that.
长官 不用担心
No worries, Colonel.
我会让这小子规规矩矩的
I'll keep this boy in line.
我也来挖
I'll dig.
我不要你帮忙
I don't need your help.
来吧 不要骄傲
Hey, come on, now, don't be proud.
我昨天恰好听到了你的谈话
I heard you talking just yesterday.
和马宏的谈话
Talking to Mahone.
你知道 关于美国人如何联合起来
You know, about how us Americans should stick together.
也会帮我离开这里的 对吧 迈克?
help me down the road, right, Mikey?
这是什么 66年还是67年的?
What is it, a '66 or a '67?
-什么? -你的车
erdon? Your car.
他在问你的气缸的年代
El quiere saber el ano.
看这里
ste aqui?
对 是66年的
Pues, es un '66.
还是我做的贡献
Y es mi preciosa.
66年的
66.
恩 这是什么 325马力?
Uh-huh. What is it, 325 horses?
多少马力的
aballos de fuerza?
375马力
375.
抱歉
Perdon a me, srita. Mm-hmm.
-他在说什么? -他认出我了 但是
What's he saying? recognizes me, but
他没意识到那是在监狱
he doesn't realize it was at the prison.
问问他 是否想赚点钱
Ask him does he want to make enough cash
在下周把车子重新上个漆
to get this car cherry by next week?
他知道我们不是在讨论车子
He knows we're not talking about cars.
没错
That's right.
斯科菲尔德 我知道你要离开这里
Come on, Scofield, I know you're getting out of here.
我听到了关于你和英国佬的事情
I heard it all about you and the limey.
老兄 我只是在修复电力
I'm just fixing the electricity, Boss.
是的 我没有伙伴 因为我很挑剔
Yeah, right, and I'm just single 'cause I'm choosy.
别逼我到处说我知道的
Don't make me tell anyone what I know.
你知道了什么?
What is it you think you know?
所谓"公司"的人想让你进来这儿
Somebody called"the Company"wanted you in here
和那个叫惠斯勒的家伙合作
to work with that Whistler guy.
-没错吧? -什么"公司"?
Am I warm? What's the Company?
他们要惠斯勒干吗?
What do they want with Whistler?
我不知道 但是你知道
I don't know, but you do.
看来你知道的并不多
Doesn't sound like you know much after all.
我不需要知道
I don't need to know
臭气熏天的时候
how to change a diaper
要怎么换尿布
to know when it stinks to high hell.
你是有目的的 斯科菲尔德
You're doing something here, Scofield.
没错 是的
You're right. I am.
我在恢复供电
I'm fixing the electricity.
你要来帮忙挖吗?
Now, you wanted to help dig?
那就挖吧
Dig.
就是这儿了
Hey, this is it.
我想我们不只是在做电工活吧
I assume we're doing more than just than playing electrician.
别担心
Don't worry.
我知道我在干什么
We're exactly where we need to be.
我觉得太热了 斯科菲尔德
Heat's getting to me, Scofield.
该休息了
It's quitting time.
你介意告诉我 他怎么会在这里吗
You mind telling me why he's even out here with us?
他猜到点什么
He knows something's up.
该死的 他怎么会知道的
How the hell does he know that?
只能说 我还是有点名气的
Let's just say I have a bit of a rep.
因为福克斯河的事情?
From Fox River?
我知道你是谁 伙计
I know who you are, mate.
最近才知道的
Figured it out just lately.
终于明白为什么他们会把你送进来
Finally made sense why they pick you
而不是其他人
of all people to send here.
别担心
No worries.
保管你的小秘密 对我有好处
It's in my interest to keep your little secret.
但是贝利克?
But Bellick?
不能相信他
Can't be trusted.
我可以搞定贝利克
I can handle Bellick.
他不在计划内
He's not in on this.
好 好吧
Okay, good.
但是马宏在
But Mahone is.
马宏?
Mahone?
他像个病猫似的
He's looking abouts stable as a three-legged chair,
他要跟我们一起越狱?
and he's escaping with us?
不 只是他自己那么以为
No, he just thinks he is.
他需要镇静剂
He needs his meds.
否则他会疯掉
Without them, he'll self destruct.
只是时间问题
It's just a matter of time.
要是他没疯呢
And if he doesn't?
我会骗他 告诉他他想知道的
I'll string him along, tell him what he wants to hear,
然后摆脱他
and then I'll cut him loose.
我怎么知道你不会对我做同样的事?
How do I know you're not going to do the same thing to me?
你不用知道
You don't.
需要帮助吗 我的朋友
You need a hook-up, my friend?
不用了
No.
别着急
Take your time.
我可不强买强卖
I don't hard sell.
我的货品不会让你后悔的
My pduct speaks for itself.
在外面 我使用一些药品
Outside, I took something.
一些需要医师处方才可买到的药 叫Varatril
It's a prescription drug called Varatril,
我在想 你是不是可以
and I was wondering if you
这里可没药房
This ain't no farmacia.
但是我这有
But what I got right here
比所有美国医生给你的东西
it's bter than anything your doctor
还要好
gave you back in the States.
那是焦油
That's tar.
来尝尝 就一点
Just take a taste, algo pequenito.
你知道的 要有约束
You know, keep it in check.
我现在没钱
I don't have any money right now.
那我也没药
Then I don't have any drugs.
但是对个男人来说 在索纳
But there are a few ways for a man
还是有些办法可以赚点小钱的
to make a few dollars in Sona
满足其他人的需要
servicing the needs of others
我个人是不感兴趣
not something I'm into
你觉得我是个废物?
You think I'm a punk?
我只是在帮你
I'm just helping you
好起来 朋友 只是帮你好起来
get well, friend, just helping you get well.
勒齐先生
Ser Lechero?
Ser Lechero.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我知道你是大忙人 但我想告诉你
Look, I know you're a busy man, but I wanted to tell ya,
我不知道迈克・斯科菲尔德到底在干什么
I don't know exactly what he's doing,
-但他只是拿你做垫脚石 -不是的 猪
but Michael Scofield's taking you for a ride. No, cerdo,
我不那么认为
I don't think so.
听着 昨天我听他说关于越狱的事
Listen, I heard him talking about escape yesterday
-关于逃离这里 -他说要越狱
about breaking outta here. It's he's talking about escape,
为什么你跑来告诉我 而不是跟他一起
why are you here telling me and you're not going with him, eh?
如果他肯我当然愿意 但是他已拒绝我了
I would if he'd let me, but he's already cut me out.
他说他没事 但是我知道
He says he's square, but I know
那个狗娘养的在计划点什么
the son of a bitch is up to something.
所以我想
So I figured,
如果我不能逃跑 我也许该告诉你
if I ain't running, I might asl tell you
然后我在这的日子会好过点
and make my time in here a little bit easier.
每个人都幻想逃出索纳监狱
Every man fantasizes about escaping from Sona.
对 但不是每个人都可以在禁入区用铁铲铲地
Yeah, but they aren't all in no-man's-land with shovels.
铁铲是我给他的 轰他出去
I'm gave him the shovels. Get him out.
我和你一样 也给过他铁铲 还有帮手
I gave him shovels too, and guys to work with, just like you.
我在他越狱的监狱工作
I worked in the prison he broke out of.
他说他是在帮我忙
He said he was doing me a favor
修理火灾引起的破坏 他点的火
fixing damage from a fire he started.
而你知道我得到什么了吗
And you know what I got?
四肢被捆 被丢在我自己监狱的下水道里
Hog-tied and left in a pipe under my own prison.
他做不了什么的
There's nothing he can do.
有士兵看着呢
The soldiers are watching him.
我也曾那么想
That's what I thought,
直到他挖地道到我的保卫室
until he tunneled out ofy guard's room.
我在外面的接线盒里埋了些东西
He's buried something in a junction box out there
然后用土盖住 我都看见了
and covered it with dirt I saw him.
你可以亲自去看
Go see for yourself.
我要是骗你就不得好死
If I'm lyin', I'm dyin'.
你在索纳总是不顺心 是吧?
Trouble keeps finding you here in Sona, doesn't it?
我们来散散步吧
Let's take a walk, eh?
有传言说你在耍我
There are rumors about that you are trying to trick me.
你让我做什么我就做什么
I'm just doing what I'm told.
为了你的小命着想 最好那是真话
Oh? Let's hope for your sake that's true.
嗯?
Hmm?
为了确认一下
But justmake sure,
我们去禁入区吧
let's go on out to no-man's-land
看看你埋了什么
and see what you buried there.
只是想要确认下
Just want to make sure
我的人是否在为长官认真工作
my men are doing a good job for the colonel.
过去
Get in there.
打开它
Open it.
把土扒开
Move the dirt.
现在就做
Now
这是传输管胶带
It's duct tape.
修补磨损的电线
To fix the frayed wires.
这就是为什么电力这么不稳定的原因
That's why the power was so inconsistent.
我不想这些胶带松掉
I didn't want the tape to come loose,
所以用土盖住
so I packed it down with dirt.
棒极了
Beautiful.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我得去把主开关打开
I got to turn the main power switch back on.
我把它关掉了 因而我们能安全工作
I had to turn it off, so we could work on the wires safely.
我要跟你一起
I'll come with you.
只是去拉一下开关
It's just a switch.
我可以自己来
I can handle it myself.
你是可以 但是你不能这么做
You can but you won't.
送水的小子 在这里呢
Hey, water boy, it's back here.
我不需要项链 只这个十字架
I don't need the chain, just the cross.
它的大小适合 而且不是真金
It's the perfect size and it's not real gold,
所以我不会触电
so it won't conduct current.
电路一直循环
Keep the circuit open
即使总开关打开了
no power even when the main switch
也没有电
is turned on.
把十字架拿出来
Take the cross out
索纳的灯又亮了
Sona lights up again.
如果勒齐知道你们在电上搞鬼
Lechero find out you messed with his electric
你就死定了
you're dead.
他永远不会发现的
That's why he can't ever find out.
现在 别想让我接应你
Now, don't make me come get you.
这里没有人能帮你
Nobody back there can help you.
这
Uh, it's
出了点问题
It's some kind of mistake.
这应该行得通的
It should be working.
我唯一的错误在于相信你
The only mistake I made was trusting you.
萨米
Sammy.
变压器有延迟
Transformer delay.
这是座古老的监狱
It's an old prison.
现在 如果你不介意
Now, if you don't mind
我想搬进我的新牢房
I'd like to move into my new cell.
谢谢你的提醒 哥们
Thank you for your words before, blanco.
为勒齐工作
Working for Lechero,
是件苦差事 了解?
not an easy field to plow, comprende?
是呀 是呀 我知道
Oh, yeah, yeah, I comprend.
你和我 我们是
You and me, we're
铁哥们 我是尼弗斯
amigos, Nieves.
当勒齐心情好的时候
When Lechero is in a better mood,
我会去帮你美言几句
I'm going to put in a goodord, help you,
怎么说的来着 知恩图报
how you say,"move up the ladder."
我很感动
I appreciate
但是
it, compadre, but I
我的经验是
was always taught
上帝会帮助那些想自救的人
that God helps those that help themselves.
上帝与你同在
Vaya con Dios.
15000美元
$15,000
-为什么? -因为那就是他想要的
Why? Because that's what he wanted.
放松 我会给你钱的
Relax. I'll get you the money.
-我们一会见 -好的
And I will meet you there. Okay.
进展的如何?
How are you holding up?
正要去把这搞定
I just want to get this done.
很好
Good.
呆在这
Stay here.
-我跟着你 -呆在这
I'm coming with you. Stay here.
-你要我呆在这里空等? -我不在乎你做什么
You expect me to stay here and wait? I don't care what you do.
你不在乎? 你不在乎谁啊?
You don't care? Who the hell are you to say you don't care?
你不是唯一一个受此事牵连的人
You're not the only one affected by this.
是的 我知道 这正是问题所在
Yeah, I know; that's the problem.
那你还要继续去我行我素?
But you will still just run off and do whatever you want?
你这人怎么
What kind of a man are you that just
他们杀了莎拉 把她的头放在了盒子里
They killed Sara and put her head in a box
他们绑架了我儿子
And they've got my son
林肯 对不起
Oh, Linc, I'm . I'm sorry.
你还在?
You still here?
勒齐想和你谈谈
Lechero wants to talk to you.
我只是去整了整头发
I was just about to get a little trim.
勒齐说我可以找任何人的
Lechero said I was looking all bhuttu
等着瞧吧
It'll wait.
知道怎么回事么?
Did you know about this?
你真不知道怎么回事?
Did you know anything about this?
我? 不 不 尼弗斯
Me? No No Nieves
尼弗斯 是我朋友
Nieves we was friends, man.
是呀
That's right
如果你明知他在注射 却不告诉我
If you knew he was using and didn't tell me
他的死就算到你头上
his death is on your head.
拜托 拜托 拜托
Patron, Patron, Patron
毒品的事我一无所知
I don't know nothing about drugs.
真不知道
I don't. I don't.
我是说 上帝呀 我
I mean, hell, I
我12岁就开始吸大麻
I tried me some reefer when I was 12,
我只剩半条命了
I almost coughed up a lung.
很好
good
那好
That's good.
蒂博格
Teodoro.
似乎队伍不好带了
There appears to be an opening on my crew.
麦格雷迪 你的十字架还给你
McGrady, here's your cross back.
谢谢
And, uh thank you.
你真有才
You're a real smart guy.
你究竟来监狱干什么?
What the hell are you doing in prison?
给
Here.
很好
It's perfect.
你怎么拿到它的?
How did you get it?
这是你想要的 对么?
It's what you wanted, right?
是的
Yeah.
干得漂亮
Good work.
那么接下来干什么?
So what's the next step?
静观其变
Uh we wait.
保持联络
And I'll keep you posted.
你知道你在干嘛么?
You know what you need to do.
你怎么想?
What do you think?
当在那修复电力时
When i fix electricity for reason,
不可能从围墙出去
but it can't have been to make that fence sizzle
那样是白白送死
like the third bloody rail.
除非你想让狱官幸灾乐祸
Unless you want to make the colonel happy.
事实上 这对我们都好
Actually, it's in both of our best
就让围墙尽可能成为不可逾越的死亡线
to make that fence as deadly as possible.
现在我们要做的
Now all we have
就是等着我哥哥
to do is wait for my brother to come through
带着掘墓人过来
with the grave digger.
很不错
This is good
是个好开端
for a start
但我希望更多
But i want more
他要更多
He wants more.
你只说15000美元
You said $15,000.
你说过15000美元的
You said $15,000
15000不过是说说的
Fifteen to listen
你说过15000美元的
You said $15,000 You said $15,000
我来处理 林肯 我来处理
We got it, Linc I got it
我要更多
i want big cash
明白吗
understand?
冷静
calm down
看看你是不是要这个
if it's money you want
不要 不要 不要
No, no, no
你他妈的在干什么?
What the hell are you doing?
我们需要他
We need him He will sell us
他拿到了我们的钱后
out to the cops after he takes
就会把我们出卖给警察的
as much as he can from us.
他在打包了
He's packing up to go.
杀了他
Kill him.
他会背叛你的 杀了他
He's going to betray you. Kill him.
好消息 马宏探员
Good news, Agent Mahone
由于胡安・尼弗斯
Due to the untimely
死得不是时候
demise of Ser Juan Nieves,
我现在已被提升为分发物质的管理员
I have now been promoted manager in charge of retail distribution
并且负责和客户联络
and customer liaison.
离我远点
Get away from me.
交易时间
All in due time.
我不是你妈妈
Now, I'm not your momma,
我也不会帮别人擦鼻涕
and I ain't one to wipe other's noses,
但我想说的是你看起来不怎么好
but let's just say you've looked better.
我不稀罕你的东西
I want nothing from you.
但我相信你需要点什么
But sure seems you need something.
归你了
On the arm.
放心使用
No strings attached.
清醒点 阿历克斯
Get your head straight, Alex.
进来 兄弟
Come on in, man.
过来看比赛 过来
Come watch the match. Come.
你们叫这个足球 是吗?
Oh, yeah. You guys call this football down here, right?
非常好 非常好
Very good, very good.
世界杯 不用戴着你们美国佬
It's World Cup football without the silly hats
那样的傻头盔
you wear in America,
横冲直撞
where they all jump on t each other
像一群疯子
like a bunch of batty boys.
坐下来
Have a seat.
过来
Come.
蒂博格
Teodoro.
咖啡?
Caf?
只有一件事情比老鼠更令我讨厌
The only thing I hate more than a rat
就是提供假情报的老鼠
is a rat with bad information.
是的 我认同你的观点
Yeah, look, I'm sorry about all that,
但我的情报绝对不会错
but my information was good.
只是斯科菲尔德实在是个狡猾的混蛋
It's just that Scofield is a tricky bastard.
他会再干其他事的 你等着看吧
He'll try something again. You'll see.
等一下 等一下 等一下
Wait Wait a minute Wait a minute
拜托 兄弟 你们要对我做什么
Come on, you guys. What are you doing to me?
拜托 我给了你们正确的情报
Come on I gave you good information
我告诉你 斯科菲尔德在计划越狱
Scofield's planning to escape I'm telling you
他是个聪明的混蛋
He's a smart bastard
拜托 兄弟 你们要干什么
Come on, you guys. Come on. What are you doing?
不要 不要
No. No.
No No.
我给了你正确的情报
Look, I gave you good information.
你今天早上说过
u said something this morning about,
如果我说谎 我就不得好死
"If I'm lyin', I'm dyin'."
我没那么残忍 你要感谢我
Just be thankful I don't hold you to that.
拜托 蒂博格
Come on, Bagwell.
帮下我 兄弟 拜托
Help me here, man Come on.
蒂博格
Bagwell
你落下了这个在你的旧房间
You left this in your old cell.
谢谢阿历克斯
Thanks, Alex.
不用客气
You're welcome.
我觉得这么重要的东西你都能忘记
It's funny that you could forget something
真的很搞笑
as important as this is.
我很感激你为我找到了这个
Well, I'm glad you found it for me.
是的
Yeah.
噢 看啊
Oh. Oh, look.
你是因为我的慈悲才活到现在 迈克
You are breathing only by my grace, Michael.
你给我记住 下一次
Now, you remember the next time that
如果你还消遣我去做无用功
you're going to send me on a goose chase.
我没有
Okay? I didn't.
不 你有
No, no. You did.
你认为你能控制我
And you think you can manipulate me,
就像你对苏克雷和图纳做的一样
just like you did to Sucre and Tweener
还有海威尔
and Haywire.
我不是你的跑腿
I'm not your errand boy.
你逃出去的时候我要跟着你
I'm going to go with you when you escape,
如果你 无论怎么样
and if you think, in any way
想摆脱我
that you'll leave me,
我会把这块金属插进这
I will put this piece of metal right in that
小小地方
very small space
就在你的双眼之间 我会的
right between your eyes. I will.
LJ和莎拉怎么样?
how's LJ? How's Sara?
他们说他们很好
They told me they're fine.
那个掘墓的人
List, uh, the grave digger
不在了
is gone.
"不在了"是什么意思?
What do you mean, he's gone?
林肯 我们没他不能成事
Linc, we can't do this without him.
我知道 所以我们才找了他的监护人
We know, we know, that's why we went to his supervisor
这家伙能提供任何人这份工作
the guy who approves any hires for that job.
只需要用点钱
Turns out he could use some cash.
兄弟 有包裹
Oye, man. Mail call.
你时间不多了
you're running out of time
我们这样逃出去吗?
This is we're getting out?
是的
Yes.
通过老朋友的一点帮助
With a little help from an old friend.
那是什么?
What is that?
凯丝利氟
Kesslivol.
能消除尸体发臭的药品
It's a chemical that kills the odors caused by decomposing bodies.
可加热到一定的温度
And when heated to a certain degree
就能腐蚀钢铁
it eats through steel.